<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mach packages: 100% standalone Zig gamedev libraries on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/</link><description>Recent content in Mach packages: 100% standalone Zig gamedev libraries on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://machengine.org/next/pkg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>C libraries / headers packaged via Zig - Mach</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/c/</guid><description>C libraries &amp;amp; headers packaged via the Zig build system Mach provides an ecosystem of C libraries via the Zig package manager.
These aren’t Zig bindings to these libraries (which we have separately), but instead are just forks of the actual project with their build system replaced by build.zig so you can depend on them and build them using the Zig package manager.
Pure forks with build.zig:
brotli harfbuzz freetype glfw basisu opus opusfile flac ogg Header packages:</description></item><item><title>Experimental libraries - Mach</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/experimental/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/experimental/</guid><description>Experimental Zig gamedev libraries The following libraries are experimental. Some are not usable yet/we expect their APIs to change substantially, while others are near promotion to being declared stable but have a few caveats.
While libraries are unstable, they live in the Mach monorepo. Once declared stable they will be exported to a separate standalone repository.
mach-sysaudio mach-sysaudio is a lightweight and cross-platform abstraction over various sound drivers, providing input and output.</description></item><item><title>mach-freetype: Ziggified FreeType 2 bindings</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/freetype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/freetype/</guid><description>Zig bindings to FreeType and HarfBuzz, featuring:
99% FreeType 2 core API coverage. (optional) HarfBuzz bindings, which is critical for proper Unicode rendering. (optional) brotli support for woff2 fonts (optional) external zlib linkage Ziggified FreeType 2 bindings As with all Mach libraries, zero-fuss installation, cross-compilation at the flip of a switch, and broad platform support is guaranteed. Quick links: mach-freetype on GitHub Features Zig bindings to FreeType and HarfBuzz, featuring:</description></item><item><title>mach-glfw: perfected GLFW bindings for Zig</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/glfw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/glfw/</guid><description>Perfected GLFW bindings for Zig As with all Mach libraries, zero-fuss installation, cross-compilation at the flip of a switch, and broad platform support is guaranteed. Quick links: mach-glfw on GitHub Perfecting GLFW for Zig (article) Features 100% API coverage, 130+ tests, etc. mach-glfw has 100% API coverage of GLFW v3.3.4. Every function, type, constant, etc. has been wrapped in a ziggified API.</description></item><item><title>mach-gpu: the WebGPU interface for Zig</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/gpu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/pkg/gpu/</guid><description>The WebGPU interface for Zig As with all Mach libraries, zero-fuss installation, cross-compilation at the flip of a switch, and broad platform support is guaranteed. Quick links: mach-gpu on GitHub Perfecting WebGPU/Dawn native graphics for Zig (article) Perfecting The future of graphics with Zig (article) Goals Allow comptime-defined interception of WebGPU API requests (comptime interfaces.) Expose a standard Dawn webgpu.h-compliant C ABI, which routes through Zig comptime interfaces.</description></item></channel></rss>