<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The project on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/about/</link><description>Recent content in The project on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://machengine.org/next/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Known issues</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/about/known-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/about/known-issues/</guid><description>Known issues If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to run the Mach examples or similar, you may be running into one of these known issues.
nixOS If you are using nixOS, we have tips on how to use Mach with it here.
Windows File not found If you encounter an error like this:
Windows does not have symlinks enabled, or Git is not configured to use them. This is very annoying and has been reported to Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>nixOS usage</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/about/nixos-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/about/nixos-usage/</guid><description>Using Mach on nixOS If you use nixOS and want to use Mach, this document is for you.
usage via nix-ld (preferred, requires unstable) Use nix-ld following e.g. this article.
For example this shell:
with import &amp;lt;nixpkgs&amp;gt; {}; mkShell { NIX_LD_LIBRARY_PATH = lib.makeLibraryPath [ pkgs.xorg.libX11 pkgs.vulkan-loader ]; NIX_LD = lib.fileContents &amp;#34;${stdenv.cc}/nix-support/dynamic-linker&amp;#34;; shellHook = &amp;#39;&amp;#39; export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=$NIX_LD_LIBRARY_PATH &amp;#39;&amp;#39;; } Then running zig build as usual:
zig build run-textured-cube Usage via shell { pkgs ?</description></item><item><title>Platform support</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/about/platforms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/about/platforms/</guid><description>Supported Zig versions All of Mach is tested with this Zig version, which is usually (but not always) the latest Zig nightly version. Sometimes newer versions will work, older versions almost never work due to occassional minor changes in the Zig standard library APIs.
Platform support We aim to support a broad array of operating systems and architectures, as long as they are reasonably used by desktop/mobile consumers, or someone would like to contribute and maintain support for them.</description></item><item><title>Project goals</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/about/goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/about/goals/</guid><description>Mach project goals For the goals of our engine itself (i.e. how we see the process of game development changing), please see the Mach engine overview.
This page covers more broad project goals that apply to all Mach projects, code, standalone libraries, etc.
Zero-fuss installation All too often we see people get a sudden burst of inspiration: "I'm going to finally start my game/app this weekend!" only to see them utlimately get bogged down by setting up their dev environment, ending their weekend with "</description></item><item><title>Stability</title><link>https://machengine.org/next/about/stability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/next/about/stability/</guid><description>What stability means to us We haven&amp;rsquo;t reached Mach 1 yet, but Mach encompasses many projects and some are more stable than others.
Area Stability Notes Engine Experimental We expect many things to change before Mach 1. Core Stable We expect some API breaking changes as we add support for more platforms, add small features, etc. Packages - Depends on the package, experimental packages will have a clear warning in the README.</description></item></channel></rss>