<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Core overview on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</title><link>https://machengine.org/core/</link><description>Recent content in Core overview on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://machengine.org/core/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Core examples</title><link>https://machengine.org/core/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/core/examples/</guid><description>Mach core examples All examples require this nominated Zig version | known issues gen-texture-light Generates a brick texture at comptime, uses Blinn-Phong lighting, and several pipelines. Move camera with arrow keys / WASD.
git clone https://github.com/hexops/mach cd mach/ zig build run-core-gen-texture-light ~800 lines of code procedural-primitives Procedurally generated geometry, implements a few different shapes (use arrow keys to switch between them.)
git clone https://github.com/hexops/mach cd mach/ zig build run-core-procedural-primitives ~600 lines of code pixel-post-process A post-processing effect which pixelates the entire screen.</description></item><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://machengine.org/core/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/core/getting-started/</guid><description>Getting Started with Mach core Here you will learn how to use mach core in your own project/repository. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, check out the examples as those describe how to actually use Mach core&amp;rsquo;s APIs, this page just describes project setup.
Check you are using the specific Zig version Mach supports Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re using the specific Zig version Mach supports - other Zig versions will not work.
Create your Zig project mkdir myproject/ cd myproject/ zig init Add Mach as a dependency Add the Mach standard library to your project so you can @import(&amp;quot;mach&amp;quot;).</description></item></channel></rss>