<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The project on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/</link><description>Recent content in The project on Mach: zig game engine &amp; graphics toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://machengine.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/faq/</guid><description>Frequently asked questions When will the engine be released? There won&amp;rsquo;t be one major event, rather it will be a bunch of small/incremental releases building up to it. You can look at the engine roadmap to get an idea of what we&amp;rsquo;re working on currently, and what will come later.
Can I use Mach to make a simple 2D game? Using the engine? Definitely not today.
Using Mach core, maybe:</description></item><item><title>Known issues</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/known-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/known-issues/</guid><description>Known issues If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to run the Mach examples or similar, you may be running into one of these known issues.
nixOS If you are using nixOS, we have tips on how to use Mach with it here.
Windows File not found If you encounter an error like this:
Windows does not have symlinks enabled, or Git is not configured to use them. This is very annoying and has been reported to Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>nixOS usage</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/nixos-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/nixos-usage/</guid><description>Using Mach on nixOS If you use nixOS and want to use Mach, this document is for you.
usage via nix-ld (preferred, requires unstable) Use nix-ld following e.g. this article.
For example this shell:
with import &amp;lt;nixpkgs&amp;gt; {}; mkShell { NIX_LD_LIBRARY_PATH = lib.makeLibraryPath [ pkgs.xorg.libX11 pkgs.vulkan-loader ]; NIX_LD = lib.fileContents &amp;#34;${stdenv.cc}/nix-support/dynamic-linker&amp;#34;; shellHook = &amp;#39;&amp;#39; export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=$NIX_LD_LIBRARY_PATH &amp;#39;&amp;#39;; } Then running zig build as usual:
zig build run-textured-cube Usage via shell { pkgs ?</description></item><item><title>Platform support</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/platforms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/platforms/</guid><description>Platform support We aim to support a broad array of operating systems and architectures, as long as they are reasonably used by desktop/mobile consumers, or someone would like to contribute and maintain support for them.
OS x86_64 aarch64 WebAssembly notes macOS ✅ ✅ last 3 major versions supported; Windows ✅ 🏃 windows 7+ supported; ARM support is WIP Linux ✅ ✅ SteamOS (deck) ✅ truly native (Vulkan); no controller/OS integration yet; demo video Browser 🏃 WebGPU not working; audio, input, recompile-on-reload, etc.</description></item><item><title>Project goals</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/goals/</guid><description>Mach project goals This page covers more broad project goals that apply to all Mach projects, code, standalone libraries, etc.
Engine goals See this page.
Zero-fuss installation All too often we see people get a sudden burst of inspiration: "I'm going to finally start my game/app this weekend!" only to see them utlimately get bogged down by setting up their dev environment, ending their weekend with "well.. at least I got the hello world running"</description></item><item><title>Stability</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/stability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/stability/</guid><description>What stability means to us We haven&amp;rsquo;t reached Mach 1 yet, but Mach encompasses many projects and some are more stable than others.
Area Stability Notes Engine Experimental We expect many things to change before Mach 1. Core Stable We expect some API breaking changes as we add support for more platforms, add small features, etc. Packages - Depends on the package, experimental packages will have a clear warning in the README.</description></item><item><title>Style guide</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/style/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/style/</guid><description>Mach code style guide Use mach.testing where applicable In the main Mach repository we have the mach.testing module, which provides alternatives to std.testing equality methods with:
Less ambiguity about order of parameters Approximate absolute float equality by default Handling of vector and matrix types You should use mach.testing wherever it is accessible (without pulling in an additional dependency.)
usingnamespace is banned usingnamespace in general is banned from use in Mach code, because it allows one to &amp;lsquo;mixin&amp;rsquo; namespaces and tends to produce increasingly worse code quality over time.</description></item><item><title>Zig version</title><link>https://machengine.org/about/zig-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://machengine.org/about/zig-version/</guid><description>Supported Zig version Mach aims to follow the latest Zig nightly version, but is sometimes a week or so behind.
We update every Mach project every few weeks and in unison with one another, so that everything works and is being tested with a specific nightly version. That is the version you are expected to use.
Download the latest supported Zig version from our pkg.machengine.org mirror:
OS/Arch Kind Download mirror Linux x86_64 Binary zig-linux-x86_64-0.</description></item></channel></rss>